<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Leonid Koftun</title><link>https://blog.sldk.de/</link><description>Recent content on Leonid Koftun</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.sldk.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to GitOps on Kubernetes with Flux v2</title><link>https://blog.sldk.de/2021/02/introduction-to-gitops-on-kubernetes-with-flux-v2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sldk.de/2021/02/introduction-to-gitops-on-kubernetes-with-flux-v2/</guid><description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re having a look at how to set up a GitOps pipeline for your Kubernetes cluster with Flux v2.
We will first go through some core concepts of Flux and then create our first GitOps workflow.
You will need access to a Kubernetes cluster, a shell interface and a Github account to follow this guide. Note that you can use any git provider (Gitlab, Bitbucket, custom) but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to modify the provided example commands.</description></item><item><title>How I build my resume from Markdown</title><link>https://blog.sldk.de/2021/02/how-i-build-my-resume-from-markdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sldk.de/2021/02/how-i-build-my-resume-from-markdown/</guid><description>I was recently inspired to update my Software Engineering resume. The problem with that was that up until now my resume was a Word docx document that I would manually export as PDF and distribute. I used to always get frustrated when I had to touch this document because I hate formatting text in Word and/or Google Docs.
After stumbling upon this Techlead video on YouTube I was convinced that I didn&amp;rsquo;t need any fancy layouts for my CV anyway and that I would go with a minimalist plain-text approach.</description></item><item><title>Hosting static sites generated with Hugo</title><link>https://blog.sldk.de/2020/01/hosting-static-sites-generated-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sldk.de/2020/01/hosting-static-sites-generated-with-hugo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m using Hugo to generate a static website / blog from markdown.
This means that I have some source files on my local machine and I run hugo to generate static html/css files. Once I have these static files I needed to decide how to publish them to the internet.
This post is a subjective comparison of possible hosting solutions when working with Hugo.
Gitlab Pages My initial plan was to use Gitlab Pages because my source files are already checked into a private git repository on Gitlab.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://blog.sldk.de/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sldk.de/about/</guid><description>Hi 👋 My name is Leo. I&amp;rsquo;m 26 years old and I do software development. I&amp;rsquo;m based in Munich.
What is this site? This is supposed to become my blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll post random stuff here. The main focus is probably software related.
Why does this exist? I don&amp;rsquo;t know honestly. I&amp;rsquo;m seeing this as an exercise for myself. We often do interesting things at work and in private which mostly go unnoticed.</description></item></channel></rss>